canterbury.com 2012-11-22

# Privacy Policy

Canterbury ("We") are committed to protecting and respecting your privacy.

This policy (together with our terms of use [click here](http://www.canterbury.com/terms-conditions-i7 "Terms of Use")) and any other documents referred to on it) sets out the basis on which any personal data we collect from you, or that you provide to us, will be processed. Please read the following carefully to understand our views and practices.

For the purpose of the Data Protection Act 1998 (the Act), the data controller is Canterbury of New Zealand Ltd, 1st Floor Houldsworth Mill, Houldsworth St, Reddish, Stockport, SK5 6DS.

**INFORMATION WE MAY COLLECT FROM YOU**

We may collect and process the following data:

  * Information you provide by filling in forms on our site Canterbury.com (our site). This includes information provided at the time of: registering to use the site; subscribing to our service; posting material; creating or updating your personal profile; taking part in a prize draw or competition, newsletters or exclusive offers via email; or requesting further services. We may also ask you for information when you enter a competition or promotion sponsored by Canterbury, and when you report a problem with our site.
  * Records of correspondence you may enter into with us.
  * Surveys that Canterbury may also ask you to complete for research purposes, although you do not have to respond to them.
  * Details of transactions you carry out through our site and of the fulfillment of your orders.
  * Details of your visits to our site including but not limited to: traffic data; location data; weblogs and other communication data – whether this is required for our own billing purposes or otherwise. We may also record the resources that you access.

**WHAT DO WE DO WITH THE INFORMATION?**

We will require you to provide personal information such as credit/debit card details and your billing address for the purposes of completing your order. We will only use this information for the purposes of managing your order or your use of the website.

Providing additional personal information is up to you. We can collect personal information for the following reasons: to enter you into contests and notify you of results; to e-mail you with updates, news and special offers; to respond to your questions or comments; to register you for certain features on the website.

Canterbury (and those people or companies employed by Canterbury who help make this website, its content and its services) will use your personal information to respond to your feedback. This can help us respond to problems, improve our services and modify what we do to suit our requirements further.

Beyond this we will not share your information with any other company without your consent unless we are required to do so by law – for example, if you have won a prize or if you have made a request for specific information. If you give us consent then we may share your information with our partners, subsidiaries or subsidiary companies so that they can contact you with relevant information, promotions, products, services, and offers.

We will never sell your information to any other company.

**IP ADDRESSES**

We may collect information about your computer, including your IP address, operating system and browser type. This is done for system administration and to report aggregate information to our advertisers. This is anonymised statistical data about browsing actions and patterns, and does not identify any individual.

**USE OF COOKIES**

We may obtain information about your general internet usage by using a cookie file, which is stored on your browser or the hard drive of your computer. Cookies are small pieces of information that can be retrieved later. They help us to deliver a better and more personalised service – and some of them are essential for the site to operate. Most last for one session or one visit to our website only. Cookies cannot be read by a website other than the one that set them. None contain information that will enable anyone to contact you via telephone, email or other means. You can configure your web browser to inform you when cookies are present or to prevent them from being set.

**BROWSE-WRAP CONSENT**

By using the website, you agree to our use of cookies.

Cookies are widely used in order to make websites work, or work more efficiently, and to provide information to the owners of the site.

**GOOGLE ANALYTICS**

You can block cookies by activating the browser setting that allows you to refuse the setting of all or some cookies. However, if you use your browser to block all cookies (including essential cookies) you may not be able to access all or parts of the website. Our system will issue cookies as soon you visit the website unless you have adjusted your browser setting to disable them.

This website uses Google Analytics, a web analytics service provided by Google, Inc. ("Google"). Google Analytics uses "cookies", which are text files placed on your computer, to help the website analyse how visitors use the site.

**WHERE DO WE STORE YOUR PERSONAL DATA?**

The data we collect from you may be transferred to, and stored at, a destination outside the European Economic Area ("EEA"). It may also be processed by staff operating outside the EEA who work for us or for one of our suppliers. Such staff may be engaged in: the fulfillment of your order; the processing of your payment details; the provision of support services. By submitting your personal data you agree to this transfer, storing or processing. We will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this privacy policy.

All information you provide to us is stored on our secure servers. Any payment transactions will be encrypted using SSL technology. Where we have given you (or where you have chosen) a password that enables you to access certain parts of our site, you are responsible for keeping this password confidential. Do not to share a password with anyone.

Unfortunately, the transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure. Although we will do our best to protect your personal data, we cannot guarantee the security of data transmitted to our site. Any transmission is at your own risk. Once we have received your information, we will use strict procedures and security features to try to prevent unauthorised access.

**USES MADE OF THE INFORMATION**

We use information held about you in the following ways:

  * To ensure that content from our site is presented in the most effective manner for you and your computer.
  * To provide you with information, products or services that you request from us or that we feel may interest you, where you have consented to be contacted for such purposes.
  * To carry out our obligations arising from any contracts entered into between you and us.
  * To allow you to participate in interactive features of our service, when you choose to do so.
  * To notify you about changes to our service.

We may also use your data, or permit selected third parties to use your data, to provide you with information about goods and services that may be of interest to you. We, or they, may contact you about these by post or telephone.

If you are an existing customer, we will only contact you by electronic means (e-mail or SMS) with information about goods and services similar to those that were the subject of a previous sale to you.

If you are a new customer, and where we permit selected third parties to use your data, we (or they) will contact you by electronic means only if you have consented.

If you do not want us to use your data in this way, or to pass your details on to third parties for marketing purposes, please tick the relevant box on the form used to collect your data (the registration form).

**DISCLOSURE OF YOUR INFORMATION**

We may disclose your personal information to any member of our group (which means our subsidiaries, our ultimate holding company and its subsidiaries) as defined in section 1159 of the UK Companies Act 2006.

We may disclose your personal information to third parties:

  * In the event that we buy or sell any business or assets, in which case we may disclose your personal data to the prospective seller or buyer.
  * If Canterbury (or substantially all of its assets) is acquired by a third party, in which case personal data held by it about its customers will be one of the transferred assets.
  * If we are under a duty to disclose or share your personal data in order to comply with any legal obligation, or in order to enforce or apply our [terms of use](http://www.canterbury.com/terms-conditions-i7 "Terms of Use") and other agreements, or to protect the rights, property, or safety of Canterbury, our customers, or others. This includes exchanging information with other companies and organisations for the purposes of fraud protection and credit risk reduction.

**YOUR RIGHTS**

You have the right to ask us not to process your personal data for marketing purposes. We will usually inform you (before collecting your data) if we intend to use your data for such purposes or if we intend to disclose your information to any third party. You can exercise your right to opt out by checking certain boxes on the forms used to collect your data.  You can also exercise the right at any time by contacting us at [customerservice@Canterbury.com.](http://www.canterbury.com/contact-us-i3 "Contact Us")

Our site may, from time to time, contain links to and from the websites of our partner networks, advertisers and affiliates.  If you follow a link to any of these websites, please note that these websites have their own privacy policies. We do not accept any responsibility or liability for these policies.  Please check these policies before you submit any personal data to these websites.

**How to unsubscribe**

Our policy is to allow users to unsubscribe from our regular emails at any time. You can do this by clicking on the ‘Unsubscribe’ link at the bottom of the email you’ve received. Should you experience any problems please call our Customer Services Team who will assist you.

If you have asked us to stop sending emails and this hasn’t happened, it may be because the email address to which we are sending them is not the same as the address you sent your request from. Please check the address we are using and include this information in your request. The easiest way to do this is to return to us the whole of the unwanted email. The address we are sending to is included within the message.

**ACCESS TO INFORMATION**

The Act gives you the right to access information held about you. Your right of access can be exercised in accordance with the Act. Any access request may be subject to a £10 fee to meet our costs in providing you with this information.

Changes to our privacy policy

Any changes we may make to our privacy policy will be posted on this page and, where appropriate, notified to you by e-mail.

**Contact**

Questions, comments and requests regarding this privacy policy are welcomed and should be addressed to [customerservices@canterbury.com](http://www.canterbury.com/contact-us-i3 "Contact us")
